# SUTAPA MAHATO

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

UI Design UX Design Figma Miro Illustrator Adobe XD UX pin Canva Whimsical Photoshop Balsamiq

#### **SKILLS**

<u>Operating System</u>: Windows <u>Tools</u>: Figma, Adobe XD, Miro, Canva, UX pin, Whimsical, Balsamiq, Illustrator, Photoshop

<u>UI Design</u>: Design system, Style guide, Iconography, Typography, Responsive Layout, Desktop Application

<u>UX Design</u>: Contextual Interview, Affinity Mapping, Card Sorting, Personas, Scenarios & User Journey, Information Architecture, Competitive Analysis

## **ACTIVITIES & ACHIEVEMENTS**

Course completion certificate by Great Learning on, " UI / UX for Beginners" online course

Course completion certificate by Great Learning on, "Intro to Graphic Design with Photoshop" online course

Got Kalaratnam Excellence Award from Kalaratnam Foundation of Art Society, got 107th position internationally

International Gold Award 'KFOAS'

Participate in National and International Art Exhibition and Camps

# **UI/UX** Designer

\$\square\$ 9832246254 @ supu2771996@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Highly motivated and creative UI/UX designer with experience in coordinating for the Government of West Bengal and currently doing an internship in a start-up as an UI/UX designer. Proficient in Figma, Adobe, Miro, and Canva. Possess good management and leadership skills. Artisan Identity card holder.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### UI/UX Designer Intern

12/2022 - 05/2023

Frutos

Bangalor, Karnataka

Worked on Mobile application UI design and Website design. In Mobile Application UI and Website design, mainly I have done Product page design, Subscription page design, Kids education section design, Gaming Banner design, Ideate and define the solution, flow and structure, Prototyping, Testimonial page design, Interface building and layout design, Typography

Coordinator 01/2018 - 12/2019

#### Global Infotech

Purulia, West Bengal

Worked on a Skill development project for West Bengal goverment, involved in Art and Handcraft projects.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Shape UP - A fitness application for pregnant women

Performed in-depth analysis using UX research methods to identify major problems and created information architecture, storyboard, and scenario. Planned the layout of the application by making high-fidelity wireframes.

https://www.behance.net/gallery/168731563/Shapeup-Women-Fitness-App-Case-Study

# Smart Watch Design - IOS (Wearable Technology

Created UI screens for Wearable Technology. Conducted research on the different types of smartwatch UI and designed an Apple smartwatch to access every activity ② https://www.behance.net/gallery/169310585/Apple-Watch-UI-Case-Study

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts in Bengali Literature 06/2017 - 06/2020

Netaji Subhas Open University Purulia, West Bengal

PGP in UI & UX

08/2022 - 03/2023

Digital Academy 360

Bangalore, Karnataka